<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An addition to Swinton's case, in relation to his father's pretended forfeiture, upon occasion of the answer to it published by the Earl of Lauderdale.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1690</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 42 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 10 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B01468</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A532AA</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R176282</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">51617778</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 51617778</idno>
            <idno type="VID">175122</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B01468)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 175122)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2713:4)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An addition to Swinton's case, in relation to his father's pretended forfeiture, upon occasion of the answer to it published by the Earl of Lauderdale.</title>
                  <author>Lauderdale, John Maitland, Duke of, 1616-1682.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>18 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[Edinburgh? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1690?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signatures: A-A², B-B², C.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Swinton, John, --  Sir, fl. 1696 --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term>Lauderdale, John Maitland, --  Duke of, 1616-1682 --  Trials, litigation, etc.</term>
               <term>Forfeiture --  Scotland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-08</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-08</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:175122:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>AN ADDITION TO <hi>SWINTON'S</hi> CASE, in relation to his Father's pretended Forfeiture, upon occaſion of the ANSWER to it publiſhed by the Earl of <hi>Lauderdale.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <hi>SWINTON</hi> having in his Printed CASE and REASONS of REDUCTION, in relation to his Father's pretended For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiture, given ſo <hi>true</hi> and <hi>clear</hi> an account of that Affair to the World, as upon the ſevereſt Scrutiny can be made into the matter of Fact, as repreſented by him, it will be impoſſible for his Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſaries ever to convell; he ſhall not trouble himſelf to take ſo much notice of the <hi>Paper</hi> publiſhed by the Earl of <hi>Lauderdale</hi> by way of <hi>Anſwer,</hi> as to make any <hi>formal Reply</hi> unto it. But the Earl's Deſign in that Paper, being only to <hi>obſcure</hi> and <hi>darken,</hi> what he found was ſet in too great a <hi>Light,</hi> for him by any other method to cope withall; and to render the CAUSE of a <hi>Son</hi> unfavourable, by reflecting upon his <hi>Father:</hi> he ſhall endeavour to take off, what therein may ſeem to have any weight with thoſe that read it.</p>
            <p>AND <hi>in the firſt place,</hi> As to what the Author of the Earl's <hi>Anſwers</hi> is pleaſed ſo virulently to libel againſt the <hi>Fame</hi> &amp; <hi>Reputation</hi> of the deceaſs'd <hi>Swinton,</hi> in the odious Compariſon he makes bewixt him and the Duke of <hi>Lauderdale,</hi> DEBASING the one as a Traitor to his King and Countrey, and EXTOLLING the other as litle leſs than a Martyr for both; thoſe who ſhall conſider the Anſwer the former gave in to the Inditement, exhibited againſt him in the Parliament 1661, will (even tho they never knew him) find him of far another <hi>Character,</hi> &amp; very clear from ſo <hi>black</hi> an Imputation: and one whoſe
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:175122:2"/> Deportment in all the Tranſactions (whether publick or private) of his Life, are ſo well known, and have left ſo <hi>fair</hi> an impreſſion in the minds of all that knew him, as whatſoever the Duke's great Merits were, in relation to his <hi>King</hi> and <hi>Countrey,</hi> the deceaſs'd <hi>Swin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton,</hi> were he living, would think he had no great reaſon to envy his MEMORY either as to the one or the other.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Whereas it is alledged,</hi> That this <hi>Swinton</hi>'s Brother did procure a Commiſſion from the late King <hi>Charles,</hi> for enquiring into the Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thod, Procedure, and the Warrants upon Record, of <hi>Swinton</hi> their Father's Forfeiture; and there being ſeveral <hi>Objections</hi> of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fered againſt the Forfeiture, and <hi>Anſwers</hi> made thereunto by the Earl of <hi>Lauderdale;</hi> the Commiſſioners were convinced, that no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing of moment was inſtructed on the Objector's part, and the Commiſſion thereupon deſerted.</p>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, That <hi>Swinton</hi>'s Brother having repre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſented to the late K. <hi>Charles</hi> the clear Grounds of <hi>Nullity</hi> of the For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiture, and the unjuſtifiable Methods had been made uſe of in the Procedure concerning it; his <hi>Majeſty</hi> found them ſo convincing, that he was pleaſed to grant a Commiſſion to the Earl of <hi>Aberdene,</hi> then Chancellor, and ſeveral others, to take tryal of the ſame, and to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port. And accordingly inquiry thereinto being made, and the Parties heard; the Lords of the Commiſſion were fully ſatisfied of the truth of what was objected againſt the Forfeiture. But by the influence the Earl of <hi>Lauderdale</hi> had upon ſeveral of them, the Report was delayed: and ſhortly after, the Earl of <hi>Aberdene</hi> being laid aſide, the Commiſſion thereby expired. So that to al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge, that the Commiſſion deſerted upon the account that there was nothing inſtructed againſt the Forfeiture, is moſt calumni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous and falſe.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Whereas it is alledged,</hi> That albeit the Warrants of the Decreet 1651 be not produced, yet the Extract muſt make as much Faith as if the Warrants were extant, ſeing the Lords of Seſſion ſuſtain all Extracts out of the Regiſters in the years 1648. 1649. 1650. and 1651. and refuſe to grant <hi>Certification</hi> againſt any Writs re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſtered
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:175122:2"/> thoſe years, becauſe the Regiſters of thoſe years were loſt.</p>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, That the pretended Extract of the Decreet 1651. can make no Faith, becauſe it is not ſubſcrib<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the Clerk Regiſter for the time, as all Extracts of Decreets of Parliament are in uſe to be. Neither is it ſo much as made ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear, that Mr. <hi>Thomas Henryſon,</hi> who is alledged to ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribe that Extract, was Clerk-depute to the Committee of E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtates. And ſeing there are no Warrants of that Decreet ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tant, it cannot make Faith. For as to what is aſſerted of the Lords of Seſſion, concerning Extracts for thoſe years, it is moſt calumnious; the Lords not ſuſtaining ſuch Extracts, to <hi>ſatisfie the Production</hi> in <hi>Improbations:</hi> but all they do is, to ſtop the Extract of the Certification for ſome <hi>time,</hi> that the Parties may raiſe a <hi>Proving of the Tenor,</hi> of any Writ regiſtered thoſe years; and allow the Parties to make uſe of any pretended Extract they have, only as an <hi>Adminicle</hi> in proving the <hi>Tenor:</hi> but do not ſuſtain ſuch Extracts <hi>per ſe</hi> to make <hi>intire Faith.</hi> Which if otherwiſe, were of dangerous Conſequence, ſince Perſons might forge Extracts of Decreets and Bonds for thoſe years, and ſo ruine whom they pleaſed in their Eſtates and Fortunes.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And whereas it is alledged,</hi> That the Truth and Veritie of the Decreet 1651, is adminiculated by this, that Lieutenant <hi>Govain</hi> who was forfeited at the ſame time with <hi>Swinton,</hi> and is contained in the ſame Decreet; was by vertue of that Decreet put to Death, by Order of Parliament, in the year 1661.</p>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, That the Parliament 1661, did not conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der that Decreet 1651, as a ſtanding Decreet againſt <hi>Govain,</hi> upon which he could have been ſummarly executed: but on the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary, he being called before the Parliament, that Decreet was given him <hi>to ſee and anſwer,</hi> by which it was turned into a <hi>Libel,</hi> and as he was to anſwer it as a <hi>Libel,</hi> ſo he did actually give in his <hi>Anſwers</hi> to it, and the Parliament gave their <hi>Sentence</hi> againſt him, as upon a Libel and Anſwers. So that <hi>Govain's</hi> being one
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:175122:3"/> of the Perſons comprehended in the Decreet 1651 with <hi>Swinton,</hi> is ſo far from adminiculating the Verity and Truth of that Decreet, that it redargues the ſame. For if the Parliament had look'd up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on that Decreet, as a true and valide Decreet; they would have ordained the Sentence therein to be put in Execution againſt <hi>Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vain</hi> without any further Demurr. But having allowed him to ſee and anſwer, it is a clear Demonſtration, that the Parliament con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidered that pretended Decreet only as a <hi>Libel,</hi> and not as a <hi>formal, standing, legal</hi> Sentence. Eſpecially ſeing upon the Anſwers given in by him, they paſſed a <hi>new</hi> and <hi>ſolemn</hi> Sentence againſt him, forfeiting his Life and Fortune, ordaining his Arms to be lacerat, and delete out of the Herald's Books, with all the other Solemnities of a Forfeiture. Which it is abſurd to think the Parliament either would or could have done, if the Decreet 1651 had been looked upon by them, as a true and valide Forfeiture; it being as repugnant to Senſe, as contrary to Law, for a Man once forfeited to be forfeited over again.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Whereas it is alledged,</hi> That the Verity of the Decreet of For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiture 1661, is adſtructed by the Liſt of the unprinted Acts, which bears that there was a Decreet of Forfeiture againſt <hi>Swin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton;</hi> and by the Act of Indemnitie, in which with other De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creets, that Decreet of Forfeiture is excepted.</p>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, That the mentioning of that pretended Decreet of Forfeiture 1661. in the Liſt or Index of the unprinted Acts, and the exception thereof out of the Act of Indemnitie, do not inſtruct that there was ſuch a For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiture. For the mentioning of a Title of Law, doth not inſtruct that there is ſuch a Law, unleſs the Law it ſelf be extant. Seing in this, as in all other caſes of the like nature, the <hi>Maxime</hi> takes place, <hi>Quôd non creditur referenti niſi constet de relato.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>And whereas it is alledged,</hi> That if <hi>Swinton</hi> had been innocent of the Crimes contained in the ſaid pretended Decreet of Forfeiture 1651, and had had any ground to have queſtioned the ſame; he would have made Application to the Parliament 1661, or to Parliaments ſubſequent, for getting the ſame reduced.</p>
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:175122:3"/>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, That it is notourly known, that the Duke of <hi>Lauderdale</hi> being the chief Miniſter of State in this Kingdom, had that Influence upon the Government all his time; that it had been to no purpoſe for <hi>Swinton,</hi> to have made any Application for re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ducing of his Forfeiture, ſo long as the Duke lived. But immediatly af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter his Deceaſſe, <hi>Swinton's</hi> Son <hi>Alexander</hi> applied to the King, and procured the aforeſaid Commiſſion, for trying the Nullity of the ſaid Forfeiture, which if it had not been made ineffectual by the Earl of <hi>Lauderdale</hi>'s means, and the Earl of <hi>Aberdene</hi>'s being turned out of Office, to whom, with others, the Commiſſion was granted; there had certainly been a Report made, finding the Nullities now al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledged againſt the ſaid Forfeiture, ſufficiently proven as they are now inſtructed. But as a convincing evidence, that the deceaſs'd <hi>Swinton</hi> did never acknowledge the Forfeiture; all was done that he could do, during the Duke's Lifetime, to recover his Eſtate from him. In order to which, ſeveral of <hi>Swinton's</hi> Friends having made Application to the Duke, they ſo far prevailed with him, and ſo conſcious was he of the invalidity of his Right; that in the year 1663, he condeſcended to accept of 5000 <hi>lib. Sterling:</hi> and was content to allow as a part of that Summ, the three years Intromiſſion he had had with the Rent of the Eſtate of <hi>Swinton;</hi> and look'd upon the Remainder as ſufficient to ſatisfie and compenſe any Intromiſſion <hi>Swinton</hi> had had with that part of the Duke's Eſtate that he had poſſeſſed the time of the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Uſurpation. Which matter of Fact, if need were, could be proved by ſeveral Perſons of quality, who communed betwixt the Duke of <hi>Lauderdale</hi> and <hi>Swinton</hi> at that time, and particularly by the Earl of <hi>Tweddale:</hi> and that the reaſon why that Communing did not take effect, was the Duke &amp; <hi>Swintons</hi> differing in the Compu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation of <hi>Swinton's</hi> Intromiſſion: the Duke computing it to amount to 5000 <hi>lib. Sterling,</hi> &amp; <hi>Swinton</hi> contending it amounted but to 4000 <hi>lib.</hi> Which clearly evinces, that as the Duke did not look upon the Forfeiture as valide and legal, ſo he never intended to make further uſe of it, than to be repayed of what he conceived <hi>Swinton</hi>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:175122:4"/> had intrometted with of that part of his Eſtate which he had poſſeſſed under the <hi>Engliſh.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Whereas it is alledged,</hi> That <hi>Swinton</hi> in his Anſwers given in to the Parliament 1661. endeavours to extenuate his Crime, in joyn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing with the Uſurper <hi>Cromwel,</hi> and going with him to <hi>Worceſter,</hi> pretending he was out of the Protection of the Law; which could only be underſtood of the Decreet of Forfeiture 1651. And that in his Anſwers before the <hi>Parl.</hi> 1661. he doth not deny his being then forfeited.</p>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, That <hi>Swinton</hi> by his mentioning in his Anſwers, that he was <hi>out of the Protection of the Law,</hi> did not under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtand he was ſo by a Decreet of Forfeiture 1651. But that he being then denounced for not Compearance, the Denounciation did put him out of the Protection of the Law. And that Expreſſion cannot be otherwiſe underſtood, ſeing in his Anſwers he makes no mention at all of that pretended Decreet of Forfeiture, 1651. And it is moſt abſurd and ridiculous to pretend, that <hi>Swinton</hi>'s not denying in his Anſwers before the <hi>Par.</hi> 1661. that there was ſuch a Decreet in the year 1651. is an evidence of the verity of it. For 1. the An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwers being made to the Inditement, and there being no mention in the Inditement of the Decreet 1651. he was not obliged to anſwer, nor take notice of any thing but what was in the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditement. 2. His Anſwers could not bear a denying of the Decreet 1651. becauſe his Anſwers were given in to the Inditement, before the Decreet 1651. was produced, or made uſe of againſt him. Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing it appears by the Lord <hi>Preſmennen's</hi> Diary, the 15 of <hi>May,</hi> that <hi>Swinton's</hi> Dittay with his Anſwers were then read before the Parliament: and that the Lord Advocat opponed the Dittay, and <hi>produced the former Decreet of Forfeiture against him.</hi> And it ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pears by a Copy of the ſaid Decreet delivered to <hi>Swinton,</hi> by <hi>Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>exander Reid</hi> the Advocate's Servant, that it was not delivered to him till the 17 of <hi>May,</hi> it being marked upon the back with the ſaid <hi>Alexander Reids</hi> hand, that it was given to <hi>Swinton</hi> the 17 of <hi>May,</hi> to anſwer the 24. Whereas it is evident by the Minute on the
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:175122:4"/> Margent of <hi>Swinton</hi>'s Anſwers, that the ſaid Anſwers were given in by him upon the 14 of <hi>March</hi> 1661. and given up to the Advo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate to ſee, which was two Months before the Decreet 1651. was produced. And <hi>Swinton</hi> being upon the 15 of <hi>May</hi> allowed to ſee and anſwer to that Decreet, he was never thereafter called before the Parliament, and ſo had never an occaſion to make any Anſwer to it.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Whereas it is alledged,</hi> That the Author of <hi>Swinton</hi>'s Caſe does ſhow his Ignorance and Diſingenuity, in aſſerting that the <hi>Restriction</hi> in the Decreet 1651. reſtricting the Sentence to the Puniſhment of <hi>John Hume</hi> to the Death, takes off the ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect of the Sentence, as to <hi>Swinton,</hi> and all the reſt; ſeing the Doom of Forfeiture was ſolemnly pronounced by ſound of Trumpet, and tearing the Arms of thoſe forfeited; and by ſeveral reiterated Acts, forfeiting them, as to Life, Heretage, and Moveables: and that <hi>Swinton</hi> did not pretend to, or found upon any Reſtriction of that Sentence, when he was brought before the Parliament 1661.</p>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, That the Penner of the Earl of <hi>Lauderdale</hi>'s Anſwers doth groſly bewray aſwell his Ig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norance as Diſingenuity in the ſaid Alledgance. For the Reſtriction in the Decreet is plain and expreſs, which is ſubjoyned after the pretended Sentence, which the King and Committee of Eſtates, for Reaſons and Conſiderations moving them, did reſtrict to the puniſhment of <hi>John Hume</hi> to the Death. Which Reſtriction be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in <hi>general Terms,</hi> muſt be underſtood to relate to all the fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentioned Perſons, and ſo clearly takes off the effect of the Sen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence, as to <hi>Swinton</hi> and all the reſt, until it ſhould be reconſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered by the King and Parliament. And there was very good reaſon for the Reſtriction, and that the Sentence ſhould have been inſtantly put in execution againſt <hi>John Hume:</hi> becauſe the Crimes libelled againſt him were moſt atrocious, being <hi>his keeping a Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſpondence with the Enemie, his diſcovering the condition of the Caſtle of</hi> Edinburgh, <hi>by throwing a Letter over the Wall to the Enemy,</hi> &amp;c. and
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:175122:5"/> the Probation was clear againſt him, he having <hi>acknowledged</hi> the Crime, before the Court-Marſhal and Miniſters of the Caſtle. Whereas there was nothing libelled againſt <hi>Swinton,</hi> except only his pretended deſerting of the King's Army, and his frequent re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidence with, and reſorting to the Enemy in the Town of <hi>Edin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>burgh, Cannongate</hi> and <hi>Leith,</hi> which could infer no Crime, far leſs the Crime of Treaſon: ſeing <hi>Swinton</hi> did not deſert the Army, but laid down his Charge, which was taken off his hand, and given to another; and all the converſe he had with the Enemy, was in the quality of a Priſoner. And as an unanſwerable evidence that it was not deſigned any Execution ſhould paſs upon the ſaid pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended Decreet 1651. till it ſhould be reconſidered, as to the reſt of the Perſons therein-mentioned; when <hi>Govain</hi> was brought before the Parliament 1661, he was (as hath been ſaid) ordained <hi>to ſee and anſwer</hi> that Decreet, not as a <hi>ſtanding</hi> Sentence againſt him, but only as a <hi>Libel:</hi> and the Parliament upon conſideration of that Decreet as a Libel, proceeded to a Sentence againſt him. As alſo when that Decreet was produced, and made uſe of againſt <hi>Swinton,</hi> he was allowed <hi>to ſee and anſwer it.</hi> All which clears beyond contradiction, that the Reſtriction was looked upon to take off the effect of that pretended Sentence in the year 1651. as to <hi>Swinton</hi> and all the reſt, (except <hi>Hume,</hi>) before it ſhould be reconſidered by the King and Parliament. Neither doth that pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended Decreet bear, that the Solemnities by ſound of Trum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pet, and tearing of Arms, were uſed in <hi>preſence</hi> of the Committee of Eſtates, as is uſually done in the caſe of all ſolemn Forfeitures: but only bears, <hi>an Order for performing of thoſe Solemnities,</hi> which never appears to have been actually done. And it is frivolous and inept to pretend, that <hi>Swinton</hi> did not found upon that Reſtri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction in his Anſwers to the Parliament 1661. ſeing the Decreet 1651. was not mentioned in the Inditement, nor was that Decreet founded upon by the King's Advocate, nor made uſe of by him a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt <hi>Swinton,</hi> for two Months after <hi>Swinton</hi>'s Anſwers were given
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:175122:5"/> in; as is clear by the Minute upon the Anſwers, and <hi>Preſmennan</hi>'s Diary.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Whereas it is alledged,</hi> That by the Law and Cuſtom of Nati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, whoſoever accepts of a military Commiſſion or Charge, he cannot at his pleaſure diſmiſs or exauctorate himſelf. And <hi>Swinton</hi> having accepted of a Charge in the Army from the King and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee of Eſtates, he could not diſengage himſelf without their leave.</p>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, That it is a great Miſtake that an Officer in an Army may not quit his Charge and Commiſſion when he pleaſes: and it appears, that what Lawyer ſoever the Author of the Earl of <hi>Lauderdale</hi>'s Anſwers may be, he is not a Souldier. For every one knows, that knows any thing of military Affairs, that a commiſſioned Officer may give up his Commiſſion, and liberat himſelf whenſoever he thinks fit to do ſo. Which being a thing of ſuch ordinary, and univerſal Practice; it is ſtrange how a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny man ſhould have the confidence to controvert it.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And whereas he asks the question,</hi> What could (whilſt his Family was on the other ſide) have moved <hi>Swinton,</hi> to come to this ſide of the Water, where the Enemy lay, and where he could not eſcape being taken; if he had not had a Deſign to have joyn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed with the Enemy?</p>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, That the deceaſs'd <hi>Swinton</hi> gives a clear account hereof in his Anſwers, before the Parliament 1661, <hi>viz. That after he had intimated to the then Chancellor, at</hi> Stirling, <hi>the laying down of his Charge, deſiring him to acquaint the Committee of Estates with the ſame; and at the ſame time intimated it to Collonel</hi> Gilbert Ker <hi>his immediat Superior Officer,</hi> Crafurdland <hi>was put into his Place.</hi> And that <hi>before he came to this Part of the Countrey where his Eſtate lay, and where his Buſineſs called him; he was up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Place where Collonel</hi> Ker's <hi>Regiment was, where he did actu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally ſee</hi> Crafurdland <hi>in his Charge: and that his Occaſions leading him to</hi> Berwick-ſhire, <hi>where the only Eſtate he had lay; he was ſeized upon and made Priſoner by a Party of the</hi> Engliſh, <hi>and car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried to their General's Quarters: and having given an account to
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:175122:6"/> him of his Occaſions in theſe Parts, the General declared to him, al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tho he was his Priſoner, yet he ſhould have liberty upon his Parole, to go to his Lodging, and about his Affairs.</hi> And both the manner of his quiting his Charge, (as thus related,) and that he was taken Priſoner, and thus brought in; <hi>he poſitively offered him to prove</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Parliament: which was unqueſtionably <hi>relevant</hi> to liberat him from the leaſt Suſpition of having any Deſign to joyn with the Enemy, and his Family was not on the <hi>other</hi> ſide, but <hi>this</hi> ſide of <hi>Forth</hi> at that time, and under the Power of the Enemy.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And whereas it is alledged,</hi> That the Decreet 1651, being ordained by the Parliament to be given up to <hi>Swinton</hi> to ſee, the 15 of <hi>May</hi> 1661. and he ordain'd to give in his Anſwers thereunto againſt that day eight days. And that accordingly he having got up the Decreet to ſee, <hi>he returned the ſame without any Anſwers:</hi> which he would not have done if he had been innocent of the Crimes libelled a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt him in the ſaid Decreet.</p>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, That the deceaſs'd <hi>Swinton</hi> ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver got the Decreet it <hi>ſelf</hi> to ſee, but only a <hi>Double,</hi> marked on the back by <hi>Alexander Reid</hi> the Advocate's Servant: and which this <hi>Swinton</hi> has yet to ſhow, and now produces. And albeit he was ordained upon the 15 of <hi>May,</hi> to ſee and anſwer that Decreet againſt that day eight days: yet he never was thereafter called be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Parliament to give in his Anſwer to it. And ſo it is falſe, that he gave back the <hi>Decreet</hi> without making any Anſwer: ſince he could not give <hi>back</hi> what he never <hi>received;</hi> and could make no Anſwer to the <hi>Copie</hi> which he did receive, unleſs he had been <hi>called</hi> to do ſo.</p>
            <p>AND here it cannot but be taken notice of, that how cautious ſoever thoſe who framed the Draught of the Decreet againſt <hi>Swin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton,</hi> which is pretended to have paſſed in the Parliament 1661. to <hi>omit</hi> out of it that Ordinance of Parliament, whereby upon the 15 of <hi>May</hi> 1661. <hi>Swinton</hi> was ordained to ſee the Decreet 1651. and to give in his Anſwer to it againſt that day eight dayes (be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:175122:6"/> the 24.) the Earl of <hi>Lauderdale</hi> is not only forced in this place of his Anſwers, to acknowledge there was ſuch an <hi>Ordinance,</hi> but afterwards, <hi>(tanta eſt vis veritatis,)</hi> to acknowledge, when he comes to quible upon the forged Minute of the 12 of <hi>July</hi> 1661, that <hi>Swinton did not compear that Day,</hi> and conſequently was never cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led before the Parliament, after the 15. of <hi>May.</hi> And it is left to all judicious Peruſers of what is now publiſhed on either hand, in relation to this Myſtery of Iniquity, (wherethrow the deceaſs'd <hi>Swinton</hi> and his Family have been ſo great Sufferers, and for ſo long a time;) to conſider, whether it be preſumable, that he being a Priſoner in the Tolbooth of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> within <hi>Call</hi> of the Place where the Parliament ſate, and a Term having been aſſigned him, to give in an Anſwer to that pretended Decreet 1651. the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, (for the <hi>Honour</hi> and <hi>Juſtice</hi> of which, the Earl takes upon him now to be ſo much concerned,) would, without calling <hi>Swinton</hi> to <hi>give</hi> his Anſwer, have proceeded to a Sentence againſt him, albe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>it the matter had been but of a <hi>civil</hi> import; or tho there had been no ſuch Term <hi>aſſigned,</hi> would have proceeded to a Sentence a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt him, in a Cauſe that was <hi>Capital,</hi> and in a Crime of <hi>Treaſon,</hi> without calling him to the Bar, to hear the ſame pronounced. Which to ſuppoſe, were the higheſt Reflection upon the Honour and Juſtice of a Parliament, that ever Man was guilty of.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Whereas it is alledged,</hi> That the Decreet 1651, bears that the Libel was found relevant, and proven by the Depoſitions of di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers famous Witneſſes, as was clearly known to his <hi>Majeſty</hi> and the Committee of Eſtates. And therefore the Decreet cannot be ſaid to be without Probation, ſeeing the way and the manner how the Libel was found proven, is condeſcended upon.</p>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, That it ſeems the Author of the Earl of <hi>Lauderdale</hi>'s Anſwers, has not conſidered the Decreet. For as to that part thereof that concerns <hi>Swinton,</hi> the Libel is found <hi>re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>levant</hi> and <hi>proven:</hi> but the manner of Probation, whether by Witneſſes or otherwiſe, is not expreſſed neither as to him, nor any other contained in the Decreet, except <hi>John Hume;</hi> as to whom the
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:175122:7"/> Libel is found proven by a <hi>miſſive Letter,</hi> and his own <hi>Confeſſion.</hi> And albeit in the end of the Decreet, it bears that the Libel was <hi>ſufficiently verified and proven, by the Depoſitions of ſeveral famous Witneſſes ſworn, examined,</hi> &amp;c. theſe are but words of Stile in De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creets of abſence, and are not to be regarded. Seing in that part of the Decreet, where the Committee of Eſtates had the Libel and Probation, under their conſideration; it bears on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, that the Libel was <hi>ſufficiently proven:</hi> without condeſcending upon the manner of Probation, whether by Writ or Witneſſes. And as a convincing evidence, that there was neither <hi>Writ</hi> nor <hi>Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſes</hi> adduced for proving of the Crime libelled againſt <hi>Swinton;</hi> (which if there had been, the ſame would have been expreſs'd;) the manner of Probation againſt <hi>John Hume,</hi> being by a <hi>Letter under his hand,</hi> and by his <hi>own Confeſſion,</hi> the ſame is particularly <hi>expreſs'd</hi> in the Decreet. And certainly <hi>pari ratione,</hi> if there had been any Probation led againſt <hi>Swinton,</hi> whether by Writ or Witneſſes, the ſame would have been likewiſe expreſs'd and condeſcended upon.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Whereas it is alledged,</hi> That the Duke of <hi>Lauderdale</hi> did not raiſe a new Inditement before the Parliament 1661 againſt <hi>Swinton, before</hi> he obtained the Gift of <hi>Swinton</hi>'s Forfeiture, ſince he ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained not the Gift till <hi>May</hi> 1661, and the Inditement was given to <hi>Swinton</hi> in the Month of <hi>February</hi> before. And that albeit the Duke had cauſed raiſe a new Inditement, after his obtaining of the Gift, and had libelled the ſame Crimes againſt <hi>Swinton,</hi> &amp; had de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigned him <hi>John Swinton</hi> of <hi>Swinton;</hi> yet that was no paſſing from the former Decreet 1651. there being Crimes added that were committed after the year 1651. and it being ordinary to deſign Perſons by their former Titles, a wrong Deſignation could not prejudge the King nor his Donatar. And that the King's Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vocate did not inſiſt againſt <hi>Swinton</hi> upon the Crimes mention<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in the former Decreet, to forfeit him of new again, upon thoſe Crimes; but did inſiſt upon the Decreet 1651, as <hi>probatio probatae,</hi> and that the ſaid Decreet might be <hi>ratified and approven,</hi> as it
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:175122:7"/> was by the Decreet 1661. and <hi>Swinton</hi> alſo <hi>of new</hi> forfeited, for his being in Arms at <hi>Worceſter</hi> againſt the King, which was the only new additional Article inſiſted upon againſt him. And that altho a forfeited Perſon in the Conſtruction of Law, be reputed <hi>civiliter mortuus,</hi> ſo that he hath not <hi>perſonam ſtandi in judicio;</hi> yet that is only <hi>in odium</hi> of himſelf, but cannot prejudge the King nor his Donatar, nor hinder a Party for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feited committing Treaſon after the Forfeiture, to be forfeited of new: no more than a Murtherer's being ſentenced to die, as a Mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therer, could hinder him, if eſcaping out of Priſon after Sentence, he ſhould commit Treaſon; to be forfeited, notwithſtanding of the former Sentence ſtanding againſt him for the Murther.</p>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, 1. That albeit the Duke of <hi>Lau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derdale</hi>'s Gift of the Forfeiture was after <hi>Swinton</hi> had received his Inditement before the Parliament 1661. yet it is notourly known, that the Duke deſign'd to have the Gift before that time, and accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dingly thereafter procured it. And albeit the Gift was obtained <hi>after</hi> the Inditement was given to <hi>Swinton;</hi> yet ſeing it was <hi>before</hi> the pretended Forfeiture 1661. it was <hi>ipſo jure</hi> null: ſince by the <hi>Claim of Right,</hi> it is declared, that <hi>the diſpoſing of Forfeitures be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore Sentence, is contrary to Law.</hi> 2. The raiſing of a new Libel againſt <hi>Swinton</hi> before the Parliament 1661, being for the ſame pretended Crimes, for which it is alledged he was forfeited by the Decreet 1651. albeit there were other Crimes added in the Libel, yet that was a clear <hi>paſſing from</hi> the Decreet 1651, as what <hi>eo ip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo</hi> was look'd upon as <hi>no</hi> Decreets it being abſolutely inconſiſtent in Law, to forfeit a man twice for one and the ſame Crime. And the deſigning the Defender <hi>John Swinton</hi> of <hi>Swinton</hi> was an evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent Demonſtration, that he was neither conſidered nor looked upon as a forfeited Perſon. For tho in ordinary Diſcourſe, Men in ſuch Circumſtances may be deſigned by their former Titles; yet it is ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diculous to pretend, that was ever done <hi>in instrumentis publicis,</hi> or can be done in an Inditement of <hi>Treaſon:</hi> in which the Concluſion being to forfeit <hi>Life</hi> and <hi>Eſtate,</hi> the deſigning the Party by an <hi>E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate,</hi>
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:175122:8"/> muſt neceſſarly infer an acknowledgment in the Drawer of the Inditement, he had that Eſtate to forfeit, and conſequently th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> it was not forfeited <hi>before.</hi> And this is a thing ſo vulgarly know<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> that if <hi>Swinton</hi> had been looked upon as a forfeited Perſon, the King's Advocate could not have committed ſo groſs a Miſtake, as to have given him the Deſignation OF <hi>SWINTON.</hi> And albeit ordinarly Errors in Deſignation do not prejudge thr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Parties; yet in this Caſe, if there had been an Error, (what in <hi>rei veritate</hi> there was not,) it behoved to prejudge the King and his Donatar, being made uſe of to evince, that the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment did not look upon <hi>Swinton</hi> then, as a forfeited Perſon. 3. The King's Advocate did not make uſe of the aforeſaid De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creet 1651. as a Probation of the Inditement 1661. but libe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the pretended Crimes, without reſpect to, or ſo much as making mention of the Decreet 1651. And when the ſaid Decreet was thereafter produced, <hi>Swinton</hi> was allowed to <hi>ſee</hi> and <hi>anſwer</hi> i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> as a Libel, and ſo it could not be made uſe of as a Probation. 4. As to that Pretence, that the Parliament did <hi>ratifie</hi> and <hi>ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prove</hi> the Decreet 1651, and <hi>of new</hi> forfeited <hi>Swinton,</hi> for being in Arms againſt the King at <hi>Worcester;</hi> it is what is abſolutly in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>conſiſtent, and <hi>repugnantia in adjecto,</hi> to <hi>ratifie</hi> a former Forfeiture and of new to <hi>forfeit,</hi> And in this Caſe, the former pretend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Decreet 1651 <hi>could</hi> not be ratified: becauſe by giving a <hi>new</hi> Inditement to <hi>Swinton</hi> for the ſame Crimes, it was <hi>paſſed from.</hi> So that if there had been any Ratification of it, ſuch a Ratification could import no more but the ratifying of a <hi>Libel,</hi> which can ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver have the <hi>effect of a Forfeiture.</hi> 5. A man that is forfeited, is not only <hi>civiliter mortuus,</hi> not having <hi>perſonam ſtandi in judicis,</hi> but alſo being forfeited, he has <hi>no Eſtate,</hi> both his <hi>Perſon</hi> and <hi>Eſtate</hi> in the Conſtruction of Law being <hi>extinct:</hi> and therefore being forfeited <hi>once,</hi> he can neither <hi>quoad vitam,</hi> nor <hi>quoad bo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> be forfeited a <hi>ſecond</hi> time. And the Inſtance of a Murtherer com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitting Treaſon, after his being condemned for the Murther; is moſt impertinent, and abſurd: there being a vaſt difference betwixt
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:175122:8"/> ſuch a one, and a Perſon that is forfeited. For a Man that is ſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenced for a Murther, his <hi>Eſcheat</hi> only falls, which carries the Right to his <hi>Movables:</hi> but his <hi>Lands</hi> and <hi>heretable</hi> Eſtate ſtill remain with himſelf, and go to his Heirs. And therefore if a Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon ſentenced for Murther, ſhould make his Eſcape, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after commit Treaſon; he may be forfeited, and his Forfeiture will carry the Right to his Lands and heretable Eſtate. But it is not ſo in the caſe of a Perſon forfeited, who what Crime ſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever he commit after, is incapable either as to Life or Fortune of a higher Puniſhment.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Whereas it is alledged,</hi> That <hi>John Swinton,</hi> by his Anſwers gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven in to the Parliament 166<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>. doth acknowledge, that he was at <hi>Worceſter,</hi> and that he went thither at the deſire of the Uſurper, which ſufficiently proves the Crime againſt him.</p>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, That <hi>Swinton</hi>'s Anſwers are opponed, which bear expreſly, that <hi>he did deny that Article of the</hi> Indite<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, <hi>as it was conceived.</hi> And tho he acknowledges that he was at <hi>Worceſter,</hi> yet he declares it was as true <hi>he went thither through the earneſt Intreaty and Importunity of him, that</hi> (though he doth ingenuouſly acknowledge he could not ſay, he uſed that as an Argu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment;) <hi>could have</hi> commanded <hi>him alongſt with him as his</hi> Priſoner, <hi>and whoſe Priſoner he was upon the matter: and that he went in no other capacity than a Traveller. And that if it ſhould have been made ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear, that ever he joyned ſo much as in any</hi> Troop, <hi>or carried any</hi> Charge, <hi>or that upon any occaſion there, in the Battel or otherwiſe, he did draw a</hi> Sword, <hi>or looſe a</hi> Piſtol; <hi>he admitted</hi> all, <hi>or any</hi> one <hi>of theſe</hi> relevant of conſent, <hi>to inferr the Concluſion of the Inditement.</hi> And as an evident Demonſtration that <hi>Swinton</hi> was not at <hi>Worceſter, hostili animo,</hi> or out of any deſign to act againſt the King, or to the prejudice of his Native Countrey; he declares in his Anſwers, <hi>he could ſay, in the preſence of the SEARCHER OF ALL HEARTS, that he thought, if the Parliament ſhould find the Inditement againſt him, upon that</hi> ſingle Head <hi>of his being at</hi> Worceſter, (<hi>as he doth look u<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pon that as the</hi> Principal, <hi>and all the rest but as</hi> Acceſſories, <hi>even in the
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:175122:9"/> intention of the Libeller;) and the Sentence that ſhould paſs, as to Life and Eſtate, were ready to receive its</hi> laſt <hi>Conſummation; he could</hi> receive <hi>and</hi> ly down under <hi>it, with a more</hi> chearful Heart, <hi>than he en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyed any time he was at</hi> Worceſter, <hi>to ſee and be Witneſs of the</hi> Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proach <hi>of his Countrey, and the</hi> Diſtreſs <hi>his Countrey men were un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der.</hi> Which Confeſſion being <hi>ſo qualified,</hi> and particularly that he was there as a <hi>Priſoner,</hi> it cannot be <hi>divided:</hi> and ſo did not prove that Article of the Inditement, and could never inferr any Crime againſt him, far leſs the Crime of Treaſon.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And whereas it is alledged,</hi> That the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Act of Indem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity did extend no further than to the King<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>s <hi>Engliſh</hi> Subjects, and not to <hi>Scotſmen.</hi> And as no Law made by the Parliament of <hi>England,</hi> could hinder the Parliament of <hi>Scotland</hi> to proceed a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt Traitors who were <hi>Scotſmen;</hi> ſo no Indemnity paſs'd in the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Parliament, could Indemnifie <hi>Scotſmens</hi> Crimes, or could hinder the Parliament of <hi>Scotland</hi> to proceed againſt them, albeit they had been particularly indemnified by the Parliament of <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, That as by the Law of Nations, Crimes may be <hi>judged</hi> and <hi>puniſhed</hi> in the Place where they are <hi>com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted;</hi> ſo Perſons committing Crimes, may be <hi>indemnified</hi> by the Supream Authority where the Crimes are committed: ſeing <hi>a judicando &amp; condemnando, ad condonandum &amp; remittendum, vale<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> conſequentia.</hi> And therefore, as the deceaſs<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>d <hi>Swinton</hi> in his An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwers urgeth (with no leſs <hi>elegancy</hi> of Expreſſion, than <hi>force</hi> of Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon,) this being a Crime alledged to be <hi>COMMITTED</hi> in <hi>England, TRIABLE</hi> in <hi>England, PARDONABLE</hi> in <hi>England, PARDONED</hi> in <hi>England,</hi> and that by him AGAINST WHOM the offence was <hi>committed;</hi> that <hi>Engliſh</hi> Act of Indemnity, if he were guilty, behoved to free him. Which being <hi>general,</hi> and ſo <hi>comprehenſive,</hi> not only indemnifying all his Majeſties Subjects in <hi>England,</hi> and <hi>Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> and the Dominions thereunto belonging; but alſo <hi>the Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects of all OTHER his Majeſties's Dominions;</hi> it muſt neceſſarly comprehend <hi>Scotſmen,</hi> that had committed Crimes in <hi>England.</hi>
               <pb n="17" facs="tcp:175122:9"/> And therefore they could not be purſued for the ſame, before the Parliament, or any other Judicatory in <hi>Scotland.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>And whereas it is alledged,</hi> That a judicial Confeſſion, emitted before a high Court of Parliament makes full Faith, albeit not ſubſcribed. And <hi>Swinton</hi> did not only emit a Confeſſion <hi>viva vo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e</hi> before the Parliament, but alſo in his Anſwers, which are ſubſcribed by him, he acknowledged his being at <hi>Worceſter</hi> with the King's Enemies.</p>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, 1. That it is denyed, that <hi>Swinton</hi> did emit any judicial Confeſſion of the Crimes libelled before the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, and there is no veſtige of any ſuch Confeſſion extant up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Record. 2. It is a great miſtake in the Author of theſe An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwers, to aſſert that a Confeſſion, albeit judicially emitted before the Parliament, ſhould make Faith, without being ſigned, either by the <hi>Party,</hi> or the <hi>Preſident</hi> of Parliament: it being againſt the Principles of Law, and incontroverted Cuſtom of all Courts of Judicature whatſoever, (whether <hi>ſupreme</hi> or <hi>ſubaltern</hi>) to ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit judicial Confeſſions, without being ſigned either by the Parties themſelves, or by the Judge that preſides. 3. As to any pretended Confeſſion in <hi>Swinton</hi>'s Anſwers; the former Anſwer is op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poned, that it is <hi>qualified,</hi> and cannot be <hi>devided,</hi> but muſt be taken as it ſtands: and which ſo taken, could never have inferr'd a Crime againſt him, much leſs the Crime of Treaſon.</p>
            <p>As to what is alledged againſt the <hi>Reaſon</hi> of <hi>Reduction,</hi> foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded upon the <hi>Nullitie</hi> and <hi>Falſhood</hi> of the Minutes; the MI<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>NUTES themſelves, that REASON of <hi>Reduction,</hi> and the Earl of <hi>CRAWF<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>RD</hi>'S LETTER, are opponed, which the Penner of the Earl of <hi>Lauderdale</hi>'s ANSWERS, finds ſuch <hi>rugged, ſtubborn,</hi> and <hi>untoward</hi> Peeces to deal withall; as all the pitiful <hi>Shifts</hi> and <hi>Evaſions</hi> he tortures himſelf with, to ſhape an Anſwer to them, ſerve but to demonſtrate to the World that they neither ARE, nor CAN be anſwered.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And whereas it is alledged,</hi> That albeit the <hi>Interlocutories</hi> had not been ſigned by the Earl of <hi>Crawfurd,</hi> yet that is no <hi>Nullity,</hi> there
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:175122:10"/> being no ſpecial Law nor Cuſtom requiring the ſame at that ti<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> And the Minutes and Interlocutories of the other Proceſſes of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>feiture againſt <hi>Govain, Guthrie,</hi> and others paſſed in that Parliame<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> are not ſigned by the Chancellor, nor Preſident.</p>
            <p>IT IS ANSWERED, That the Alledgence is moſt <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>lumnious. For it was the conſtant Cuſtom of the Parliament 16<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> and hath been in other Parliaments, both preceeding and ſub<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>quent, for the Chancellor or Preſident, as they ſign all the <hi>W<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>rants</hi> for the ACTS and STATUTES that paſs in Parliame<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> ſo they are in uſe to ſign all Minutes, that are <hi>Warrants</hi> for D<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>CREETS and SENTENCES; as is evident from the RECORD<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and particularly, in the Minutes of thoſe very Sentences againſt <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>vain</hi> and <hi>Guthrie,</hi> in the Parliament 1661. mentioned in the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ledgence: &amp; of thoſe in the ſame Parliament, pronounced againſt <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Marqueſs, and late Earl of <hi>Argile,</hi> (then Lord <hi>Lor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>) Ardkinglaſs,</hi> &amp;<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> And it were againſt Senſe to think, that a Minute of a <hi>Clerk</hi> ſhou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> take away a Man's Life and Fortune, without being ſigned <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the Chancellor, or Preſident of Parliament.</p>
            <p>IN RESPECT OF ALL WHICH<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
               <hi>Swinton</hi>'s REASONS OF REDUCTIO<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> (which are inſtantly verified and inſtructed; <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ought to be <hi>ſuſtained:</hi> and the ACT given in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> him, <hi>reducing</hi> the aforeſaid two pretended Decree<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of Forfeiture, ought to <hi>paſs,</hi> and he to be <hi>reſtor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> againſt the ſame by WAY OF JUSTICE<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
